Western Federation of Miners International Mine, Mill and Smelter Workers Records 5268
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
Western Federation of Miners International Mine, Mill and Smelter Workers Records
1893-1962
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
Western Federation of Miners
International Union of Mine, Mill, and Smelter Workers
5268
4.61 cubic feet
4.6 linear ft.
Albumen prints, constitutions, agreements.
Consist of documents collected by Professor Vernon H. Jensen for his work on the non-ferrous metals industry, specifically, relating to the WFM, the IUMMSW, and the Industrial Workers of the World (IWW). Includes constitutions, collective bargaining agreements, proceedings of concentions and minutes chiefly of the WFM and IUMMSW (1893-1943). Also, documentation relating to the rank and file orevolt of Butte, Montana, Local 1 (1955) and to the rivalry between the IUMMSW and the IWW (1917-1919), among other subjects.
3834435
General
Contact Information:
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation and Archives Martin P. Catherwood Library 227 Ives Hall Cornell University Ithaca, NY 14853 (607) 255-3183> kheel_center@cornell.edu http://www.ilr.cornell.edu/library/kheel-center
Compiled by:
Kheel Staff, May 02, 2013
EAD encoding:
Randall Miles, February 23, 2017
Biographical / Historical
The Western Federation of Miners (WFM) and its successor, the International Union of Mine, Mill and Smelter Workers (IUMMSW) were historically considered the radical wing of the non-ferrous metals miners' unions.
Scope and Contents
Includes constitutions of the Western Federation of Miners (1893-1914); Grass Valley Miners' Union (1902); Poney Miners' and Millmen's Union (1906); Tintic District Miners' Union, Local 151 of the WFM (1914); the American Federation of Labor (1929); Non-Ferrous Metals Council (1952); Silver Bow Trades and Labor Council (A.F. of L.) (1930); Industrial Workers of the World (1922); International Union of Mine, Mill and Smelter Workers (1918, 1927-1940); Butte Miners' Union (1934-1943); Butte Stationary Engineers' Union, Local 83 (1927); and Great Falls Mill and Smeltermen's Union, Local 16 of the IUMMSW (1931).
Additionally, include collective agreements of the Anaconda Copper Mining Company with the American Federation of Labor, Building and Construction Trades Department and various unions (1944): Anaconda Mill and Smelters' Union, Local 117 (1944, 1952), Butte Miners' Union, Local 1 (1936-1944, 1951), and the Great Falls Mill and Smelters' Union, Local 16 (1951); Utah Copper Company with the IUMMSW District No. 2 (1946) and various unions (1944-1946); and the Kennecott Copper Corporation with the Operating Engineers Union, Local 3 (1951).
Also, minute books of the Bingham Miners' Union, Local 67 (1904-1908), and Local 1 (1925-1931). Materials interfiled with the minute books of the Bingham Miners' Union include: manuscript notes and letters on membership organizing, resignation of union members, union election, defense fund, investigation of J.A. Boyle (member, Bingham Miners' Union) for misappropriation of union funds, and memorials for deaths of union members; letters and statements regarding Bingham miners' condemnation of Governor Frank Gooding (Idaho), and Governor Jesse MacDonald (Colorado) for conspiring to murder George Pettibone (president, WFM) (1906) and Bingham miners' demands that the marshall of the town be a union member and Socialist Party representative (1905); circular letters to members regarding political changes in the WFM and rivalry for political leadership (1916); union election ballots; and photographs of miners' homes in Bingham County, Utah (1906).
Conditions Governing Access
Access to the collections in the Kheel Center is restricted. Please contact a reference archivist for access to these materials.
Related Materials
Related Collections: 5409 mf: Western Federation of Miners Constitutions on Microfilm 5410 mf: International Union of Mine, Mill, and Smelter Workers Constitutions on Microfilm 5412: Western Federation of Miners Parker Trial Proceedings on CD 5412 mf: Western Federation of Miners and International Mine, Mill and Smelter Workers Records on Microfilm
Labor unions -- Utah -- Bingham -- Political activity; Foreign workers -- Civil rights -- United States; Centralia Massacre, 1919.; Collective bargaining -- Mining industry -- Montana -- Butte; Collective labor agreements -- Mining industry -- United States; Copper mining -- Montana; Hours of labor -- Law and legislation -- Montana; Independent unions -- Miners -- Montana; IWW Deportation, Bisbee, Ariz., 1917; Labor violence -- United States; Mining -- United States -- Technological innovations; Nonferrous metal industries -- United States -- Defense measures; Strikes and lockouts -- Copper mining -- Michigan; Strikes and lockouts -- Nonferrous metal industries -- Arizona; Strikes and lockouts -- Nonferrous metal industries -- Arizona -- Jerome -- 1917; Strikes and lockouts -- Nonferrous metal industries -- Colorado; Strikes and lockouts -- Nonferrous metal industries -- Idaho; Strikes and lockouts -- Nonferrous metal industries -- Montana; Strikes and lockouts -- Nonferrous metal industries -- United States; Strikes and lockouts -- Nonferrous metal industries -- Utah; Strikes and lockouts -- Nonferrous metal industries -- West (U.S.); Strikes and lockouts -- Zinc mining -- United States; Labor union expulsion -- United States; Labor unions -- Officials and employees; Labor union structure -- United States; Construction workers -- Labor unions -- United States; Copper miners -- Labor unions -- United States; Iron and steel workers -- Labor unions -- United States; Lumbermen -- Labor unions -- United States; Metal-workers -- Labor unions -- Connecticut -- Waterbury -- Jurisdictional disputes; Metal-workers -- Labor unions -- Jurisdictional disputes; Metal-workers -- Labor unions -- United States; Miners -- Labor unions -- Arizona -- Jerome -- 1917; Miners -- Labor unions -- Colorado; Miners -- Labor unions -- Idaho; Miners -- Labor unions -- Montana; Miners -- Labor unions -- United States; Miners -- Labor unions -- United States -- Disaffiliation; Miners -- Labor unions -- United States -- Interviews; Miners -- Labor unions -- United States -- Local unions; Labor unions -- United States -- Disaffiliation; Labor unions -- United States -- Elections of officials; Labor unions -- United States -- Local unions; Labor unions -- United States -- Songs and music; Labor unions -- Jurisdictional disputes -- West (U.S.); Wages -- Law and legislation -- Montana; Wages -- Minimum wage -- Law and legislation -- Montana; Wages -- Nonferrous metal industries -- United States; Working conditions -- Nonferrous metal industries -- United States; United Verde Mines Strike, Jerome, Ariz., 1917; Liberty (Mont.) Miners strike, 1934; United Verde Mines Strike, Jerome, Ariz., 1917; Liberty (Mont.) Miners strike, 1934; Solidarity; Labor unions; Boyce, Edward.; Brown, Thomas H., 1934; Burns, William (William John), 1861-1932.; Campbell, Thomas E. (Thomas Edward), 1878-1944.; Cannon, Joseph; Clark, Charles (Charles Walker), 1871-1933.; Coles, George R.; Davidson, Robert J.; Davis, W. F., 1903; Donnelly, J. H.; Eckert, Ken; Edwards, Frank J.; Foster, Thomas, 1903-; French, Thomas; Gooding, Frank R. 1928.; Jensen, Vernon H.; Kirby, George T.; MacDonald, Jesse (Jesse Juan); McBride, John; McClusky, H. S.; McLenegan, Lew J.; Murray, Philip, 1886-1952; Parker, Sherman, 1903-; Peabody, James H. (James Hamilton), 1852-1917; Pease, Harlow; Pettibone, George A.; Powell, George; Robinson, James, 1933; Robinson, Reid; Silvey, Ted F.; Steunenberg, Frank W., 1861-1905; Stutz, R. L. (Robert Louis), 1917-; Tally, Robert (Robert Emmet), 1877-1936; Temme, Fred; American Brass Company; American Civil Liberties Union; American Zinc Company of Illinois; Anaconda Copper Mining Company; Ansonia Brass Workers' Union; Bridgeport Brass Company; Colorado. Industrial Commission; Colorado Mine Operators' Association; Copper Country Commercial Club of Michigan; Industrial Workers of the World; International Union of Mine, Mill, and Smelter Workers; International Union of Mine, Mill, and Smelter Workers. Local 1 (Butte, Mont.); Kennecott Copper Corporation; Metal Mine Workers' Union (Butte, Mont.); National Association of Die Casting Workers; New York State School of Industrial and Labor Relations; Pinkerton's National Detective Agency; Provisional Metalworkers' Council (CIO); State Mining Council (Mont.); Thiel Detective Agency; United States. President's Mediation Commission; Verde Mine Operators Association; Western Federation of Miners; Western Federation of Miners. Local 67 (Bingham, Utah)
3834435
- Constitutions, 1901-1939 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Item 1: Constitution, 1929; Publication (Box 1, Folder 1)
    Scope and Contents
    Author: American Federation of Labor
    Format: Publication
    Language: English.
  - Item 2: Preamble and Constitution, 1922; Publication (Box 1, Folder 1)
    Author: Industrial Workers of the World
  - Item 3: Constitution, 1918; Publication (Box 1, Folder 1)
    Author: International Union of Mine, Mill and Smelter Workers (IUMMSW)
  - Item 4: Constitution, 1918; Publication (Box 1, Folder 1)
    Notes: Copy 2
  - Item 5: Constitution, 1927; Publication (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Item 6: Constitution, 1927; Publication (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Item 7: Constitution, 1928; Publication (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Item 8: Constitution, 1936; Publication (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Item 9: Constitution, 1936; Publication (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Item 10: Constitution, 1938; Publication (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Item 11: Constitution, 1939; Publication (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Item 12: Constitution, 1940; Publication (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Item 13: Constitution, 1942; Publication (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Item 14: Constitution, 1943; Publication (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Item 15: Constitution, 1944; Publication (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Item 16: Constitution, 1944; Publication (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Item 17: Constitution, 1946; Publication (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Item 18: Declaration of Principles, Constitution, By-Laws, and Rules of Order, 1930; Publication (Box 1, Folder 1)
    Author: Silver Bow Trades and Labor Council, AFL
  - Item 19: Constitution, 1914; Publication (Box 1, Folder 1)
    Author: Western Federation of Miners (WFM)
  - Item 20: Constitution of the International Union of Mine, Mill and Smelter Workers, 1938; Publication (Box 1, Folder 1)
    Author: International Union of Mine, Mill and Smelter Workers
    Notes: As adopted by Thirth-fifth Convention August 1938 and Referendum Vote
  - Item 21: Constitution of the International Union of Mine, Mill and Smelter Workers, 1939; Publication (Box 1, Folder 1)
    Notes: Local Union By-Laws Appended as adopted by Thirty-sixth Convention August 1939 and Referendum Vote-notes written on constitution booklet
  - Item 22: Constitution of the International Union of Mine, Mill and Smelter Workers, 1940; Publication (Box 1, Folder 1)
    Notes: Local Union By-Laws Appended as Adopted by Thirty-seventh Convention August, 1940 and Referendum Vote
- Constitutions and By-Laws, 1893-1952 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Item 1: Constitution and By-Laws, Publication (Box 1, Folder 2)
    Author: Butte Miners' Union No. 1 (IUMMSW)
  - Item 2: Constitution and By-Laws, Publication (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Item 3: Constitution and By-Laws, 1934; Publication (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Item 4: Constitution and By-Laws, 1934; Publication (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Item 5: Constitution and By-Laws, 1934; Publication (Box 1, Folder 2)
    Notes: Copy 3
  - Item 6: Constitution and By-Laws, 1937; Publication (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Item 7: Constitution and By-Laws, 1937; Publication (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Item 8: Constitution and By-Laws, 1937; Publication (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Item 9: Constitution and By-Laws, 1939; Publication (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Item 10: Constitution and By-Laws, Wage Scale and Agreement, 1939; Publication (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Item 11: Constitution and By-Laws, 1943; Publication (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Item 12: Constitution and By-Laws, 1927; Publication (Box 1, Folder 2)
    Author: Butte Stationary Engineers' Union No. 83 (IUMMSW)
  - Item 13: Constitution, By-Laws and Rules of Order, 1902; Publication (Box 1, Folder 2)
    Author: Grass Valley Miners' Union No. 90 (WFM)
  - Item 14: Constitution and By-Laws, 1931; Publication (Box 1, Folder 2)
    Author: Great Falls Mill and Smeltermen's Union No. l6 (lUMMSW)
  - Item 15: Constitution and By-Laws, 1931; Publication (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Item 16: Constitution and By-Laws, 1952; Publication (Box 1, Folder 2)
    Author: Non-Ferrous Metals Council, AFL
  - Item 17: Constitution, By-Laws, Order of Business and Rules of Order, 1906; Publication (Box 1, Folder 2)
    Author: Pony Miners' and Millmen's Union (WFM)
  - Item 18: Constitution, By-Laws, Order of Business and Rules of Order, 1906; Publication (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Item 19: Constitution, By-Laws, Order of Business and Rules of Order, 1914; Publication (Box 1, Folder 2)
    Author: Tintic District Miners' Union No. 151 (WFM)
  - Item 20: Constitution and By-Laws, 1897; Publication (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Item 21: Constitution and By-Laws, 1897; Publication (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Item 22: Constitution and By-Laws, 1901; Publication (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Item 23: Constitution and By-Laws, 1901; Publication (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Item 24: Constitution and By-Laws, 1901; Publication (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Item 25: Constitution and By-Laws, 1901; Publication (Box 1, Folder 2)
    Notes: Copy 4
  - Item 26: Constitution and By-Laws, 1901; Publication (Box 1, Folder 2)
    Notes: Copy 5
  - Item 27: Constitution and By-Laws, 1903; Publication (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Item 28: Constitution and By-Laws, 1912; Publication (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Item 29: Constitution and By-Laws, 1912; Publication (Box 1, Folder 2)
- International Union of Mine and Mill Workers - Proceedings. Salt Lake City, Utah., 1934; Publication (Box 1, Folder 3)
  August 6, 8, and 9 1934 (August 7 proceedings not included)
  - Item 1: Proceedings of the Thirty-First Convention, 1934; Publication (Box 1, Folder 3)
    Notes: Salt Lake City, Utah. First day, August 6, 1934
  - Item 2: Proceedings of the Thirty-First Convention, 1934; Publication (Box 1, Folder 3)
    Notes: Salt Lake City, Utah. First day, August 6, 1934. Copy 2.
  - Item 3: Proceedings of the Thirty-First Convention, 1934; Publication (Box 1, Folder 3)
    Notes: Salt Lake City, Utah. Third day, August 8, 1934
  - Item 4: Proceedings of the Thirty-First Convention, 1934; Publication (Box 1, Folder 3)
    Notes: Salt Lake City, Utah. Third day, August 8, 1934. Copy 2
  - Item 5: Proceedings of the Thirty-First Convention, 1934; Publication (Box 1, Folder 3)
    Notes: Salt Lake City, Utah. Fourth day, August 9, 1934
  - Item 6: Proceedings of the Thirty-First Convention, 1934; Publication (Box 1, Folder 3)
    Notes: Salt Lake City, Utah. Fourth day, August 9, 1934. Copy 2.
- International Union of Mine and Mill Workers - Proceedings, 1948; Publication (Box 1, Folder 4)
  San Francisco, California. September 1948
  - Item 1: Program of the 44th Convention, 1948; Publication (Box 1, Folder 4)
    Notes: San Francisco, California. September 13-17, 1948.
- International Union of Mine and Mill Workers - Monthly Reports of the Secretary-Treasurer, 1934; Publication (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Item 1: Report of the Secretary-Treasurer, 1934; Publication (Box 1, Folder 5)
    Notes: November 1, 1934.
  - Item 2: Report of the Secretary-Treasurer, 1934; Publication (Box 1, Folder 5)
    Notes: October 1, 1934.
  - Item 3: Audit Report, 1934; Publication (Box 1, Folder 5)
    Author: Lincoln G. Kelly and Company
    Notes: August 3, 1934.
  - Item 4: Report of the Secretary-Treasurer, 1934; Publication (Box 1, Folder 5)
    Notes: August 1, 1934.
  - Item 5: Report of the Secretary-Treasurer, 1934; Publication (Box 1, Folder 5)
    Notes: July 1, 1934.
  - Item 6: Report of the Secretary-Treasurer, 1934; Publication (Box 1, Folder 5)
    Notes: June 1, 1934.
  - Item 7: Report of the Secretary-Treasurer, 1934; Publication (Box 1, Folder 5)
    Notes: April 1, 1934.
  - Item 8: Report of the Secretary-Treasurer, 1934; Publication (Box 1, Folder 5)
    Notes: Marrch 1, 1934.
- International Union of Mine and Mill Workers, District 5, Bessemer, Alaska - Proceedings, 1934; Publication (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Item 1: Proceedings of the First Annual Convention, 1934; Publication (Box 1, Folder 6)
    Author: International Union of Mine, Mill and Smelter Workers (IUMMSW) District #5
    Notes: Bessemer, Alabama. October 1 to October 4, 1934.
- Non-Ferrous Metals Council (American Federation of Labor) - Proceedings, 1951-1952 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Item 1: Minutes, 1951; Publication (Box 1, Folder 7)
    Notes: Salt Lake City, Utah. November 14 and 15, 1951.
  - Item 2: Minutes, 1952; Publication (Box 1, Folder 7)
    Notes: Salt Lake City, Utah. April 24 and 25, 1952.
  - Item 3: Minutes, 1952; Publication (Box 1, Folder 7)
    Notes: Salt Lake City, Utah. April 24 and 25, 1952. Copy 2.
- United Steelworkers, Boston, Massachusetts - Proceedings, 1948; Publication (Box 1, Folder 8)
  May 13, 1948
  - Item 1: Proceeding of the Fourth Constitutional Convention, 1948; Publication (Box 1, Folder 8)
    Author: United Steelworkers of America
    Notes: Boston, Massachusetts. For the third day of the convention, May 13, 1948 only.
- Western Federation of Miners Convention - President's Address, 1905; Publication (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Item 1: Address of President Moyer, 1905; Publication (Box 1, Folder 9)
    Author: Charles H. Moyer
    Notes: To the delegates of the thirteenth annual convention, Salt Lake City, Utah, May 22, 1905
- Western Federation of Miners - Proceedings. Salt Lake City, Utah., 1905; Publication (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Item 1: Proceedings of the Thirteenth Annual Convention, 1905; Publication (Box 1, Folder 10)
    Notes: Salt Lake City, Utah, May 22 to June 9, 1905
- Western Federation of Miners - Proceedings. Denver, Colorado, 1906; Publication (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Item 1: Proceedings of the Fourteenth Annual Convention, 1906; Publication (Box 1, Folder 11)
    Notes: Denver, Colorado, May 28 to June 13, 1906
- Western Federation of Miners - Proceedings. Denver, Colorado., 1907; Publication (Box 1, Folder 12)
  Bound Volume
  - Item 1: Proceedings of the Fifteenth Annual Convention, 1907; Publication (Box 1, Folder 12)
    Notes: Denver, Colorado, June 10 to July 3, 1907.
- Western Federation of Miners Convention - President's Report., 1908; Publication (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Item 1: Report of Charles H. Moyer, President WFM, 1908; Publication (Box 1, Folder 13)
    Notes: To the sixteenth annual convention, Denver, Colorado, July 13, 1908
- Western Federation of Miners - Proceedings. Denver, Colorado., 1909; Publication (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Item 1: Proceedings of the Seventeenth Annual Convention, 1909; Publication (Box 1, Folder 14)
    Notes: Denver, Colorado, July 12 to August 3, 1909.
- Western Federation of Miners Convention - President's Report, 1911; Publication (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Item 1: Report of Charles H. Moyer, President WFM, 1911; Publication (Box 1, Folder 15)
    Notes: To the nineteenth annual convention, Butte, Montana, July 17, 1911
- Western Federation of Miners - Proceedings. Victor, Colorado, 1912; Publication (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Item 1: Proceedings of the Twentieth Annual Convention, 1912; Publication (Box 1, Folder 16)
    Notes: Victor, Colorado, July 15 to July 26, 1912.
- Agreements, 1936-1952 (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Item 1: Agreement re: Working Conditions and Wages, 1944; Publication (Box 1, Folder 17)
    Author: Anaconda Copper Mining Co.; Anaconda Mill and Smeltermen's Union no. 117
    Notes: October 1, 1944.
  - Item 2: Agreement re: Working Conditions and Wages, 1944; Publication (Box 1, Folder 17)
    Author: Anaconda Copper Mining Co.; Butte Stationary Engineers' Union no. 83
  - Item 3: Agreement re: Working Conditions and Wages, 1944; Publication (Box 1, Folder 17)
    Author: Anaconda Copper Mining Co.; International Brotherhood of Electrical Workers, Locals B-65, 122, and 200
  - Item 4: Agreement re: Working Conditions and Wages, 1944; Publication (Box 1, Folder 17)
    Author: Anaconda Copper Mining Co.; Building and Construction Trades Department, AFL; Metal Trades Department, AFL
    Notes: September 18, 1944. Includes: Bricklayers, Masons and Plasterers International of America; Brotherhood of Painters, Decorators, and Paperhangers; International Association of Bridge, Structural and Ornamental Iron Workers; International Association of Mac
  - Item 5: Agreement re: Working Conditions and Wages, 1939; Publication (Box 1, Folder 17)
    Author: Anaconda Copper Mining Co.; Butte Miners' Union no. 1
    Notes: October 1, 1939.
  - Item 6: Agreement re: Working Conditions and Wages, 1941; Publication (Box 1, Folder 17)
    Notes: October 1, 1941.
  - Item 7: Agreement re: Working Conditions and Wages, 1944; Publication (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Item 8: Pension Plan Agreement and Pension Plan, 1952; Publication (Box 1, Folder 17)
    Author: Anaconda Mill and Smeltermen's Union No. 117; Anaconda Copper Mining Co.
    Notes: March 14, 1952.
  - Item 9: Agreement, 1936; Publication (Box 1, Folder 17)
    Author: Butte Miners' Union No. 1; Anaconda Copper Mining Co.
    Notes: October 1, 1936.
  - Item 10: Supplemental Agreement, 1951; Publication (Box 1, Folder 17)
    Notes: November 13, 1951.
  - Item 11: Agreement, 1946; Publication (Box 1, Folder 17)
    Author: Arthur-Magna Millmen's Union, Local 392; Utah Copper Co.
    Notes: July 1, 1946.
  - Item 12: Supplemental Agreement, 1951; Publication (Box 1, Folder 17)
    Author: Great Falls Mill and Smeltermen's Union No. 16; Anaconda Copper Mining Co.
  - Item 13: Exerpts from Agreement, 1951-1952 (Box 1, Folder 17)
    Author: Kennecott Copper Corporation; Operating Engineers Local Union No. 3
    Notes: Agreement runs from July 1, 1951 to June 30, 1952.
  - Item 14: Agreement, 1944; Publication (Box 1, Folder 17)
    Author: Utah Copper Mining Co.; System Federation no. 155
    Notes: June 1, 1944.
  - Item 15: Agreement, 1946; Publication (Box 1, Folder 17)
    Author: Utah Copper Mining Co.; Non-Ferrous Clerical and Technical Workers, Local 692
  - Item 16: Agreement, 1945-1946 (Box 1, Folder 17)
    Author: Utah Copper Mining Co.; International Association of Machinists, Lodge 568 and District 114
    Notes: June 30, 1945; amended June 22, 1946.
  - Item 17: Agreement, 1945-1946 (Box 1, Folder 17)
    Author: Utah Copper Mining Co.; International Brotherhood of Electrical Workers, Local B- 1081
    Notes: Bingham Canyon Mines only. July 1, 1945; amended June 22, 1946.
  - Item 18: Agreement, 1945; Publication (Box 1, Folder 17)
    Author: Utah Copper Mining Co.; Operating Engineers Local Union No. 3
    Notes: July 1, 1945.
  - Item 19: Contract of Wage and Working Conditions, 1944; Publication (Box 1, Folder 17)
    Author: Utah Copper Mining Co.; Brotherhood of Locomotive Firemen and Enginemen
    Notes: Bingham Canyon Mine, revised May 25, 1944.
  - Item 20: Agreement, 1946; Publication (Box 1, Folder 17)
    Author: Utah Copper Mining Co.; Bingham Open-Pit Miners' Union no. 485
  - Item 21: Agreement, 1944-1946 (Box 1, Folder 17)
    Author: Utah Copper Mining Co.; International Brotherhood of Electrical Workers, Local B- 1438
    Notes: Central Power Station, October 9, 1944; amended July 1, 1946.
- Congress of Industrial Organizations - Union Publications, 1947-1950 (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Item 1: Report to President Philip Murray, 1947; Publication (Box 1, Folder 18)
    Author: CIO, Committee Appointed to Investigate Breach Within the International Union of Mine, Mill and Smelter Workers.